<?xml version="1.0"?>
<info>
	<id>brute_force_protection</id>
	<name>Brute-Force Protection</name>
	<description>
A brute-force attack consists of an attacker trying many user passwords with the hope of eventually guessing correctly and gaining access to a user account. Frequently such attacks are conducted in an automated way which allows attackers to try many different combinations in a short time frame. In addition attackers may use dictionaries to reduce the amount of potential combinations to actual words ("dictionary attack"). Depending on the strength of a password you can estimate the amount of attempts and the respective time it will take to break it and gain access to user data. Administrators should be aware of this potential threat and take appropriate counter-measures.

The **Brute-Force Protection** extension allows administrators to specify a limit on the amount of unsuccessful login attempts. Once the limit is approached ownCloud will save ("ban") the IP address the unsuccessful login attempts were conducted from and restrict login for the combination of the user account in context and the IP address for a configurable time frame. With this an attacker is forced to either change their IP address or wait for the ban time to run-off in order to continue the attack. This best-practice approach increases the amount of time required to try a certain amount of combinations drastically making attacks unfeasible and mitigating risks to a minimum.

Additionally administrators can take further measures by requiring a high level of password strength using the [Password Policy](https://marketplace.owncloud.com/apps/password_policy) extension.
Furthermore two- or multi-factor authentication can be used to even theoretically make brute-force attacks impossible by requiring additional factors (e.g., a time-based one-time password) alongside the user password. See the [2-Factor Authentication](https://marketplace.owncloud.com/apps/twofactor_totp) extension, [more sophisticated MFA solutions](https://marketplace.owncloud.com/apps/category/security) or outsourcing user authentication to an Identity Provider via the [SAML/SSO Integration](https://marketplace.owncloud.com/apps/user_shibboleth) for further information.</description>
	<summary>Prevent attackers from guessing user passwords</summary>
	<licence>GPLv2</licence>
	<author>Semih Serhat Karakaya</author>
	<version>1.0.0</version>
	<namespace>BruteForceProtection</namespace>
	<use-migrations>true</use-migrations>
	<dependencies>
		<owncloud min-version="10.0.3" max-version="10.1" />
	</dependencies>
	<types>
		<prelogin/>
	</types>
	<category>security</category>
	<screenshot>https://raw.githubusercontent.com/owncloud/brute_force_protection/7258b38283af4e3fd8a0f03084694b6ff6339505/screenshots/brute-force-protection.jpg</screenshot>
	<settings>
		<admin>OCA\BruteForceProtection\Panels\AdminPanel</admin>
	</settings>
	<documentation>
		<admin>https://doc.owncloud.com/server/latest/admin_manual/configuration/server/security/password_policy.html</admin>
	</documentation>
	<website>https://github.com/owncloud/brute_force_protection</website>
	<bugs>https://github.com/owncloud/brute_force_protection/issues</bugs>
	<repository type="git">https://github.com/owncloud/brute_force_protection.git</repository>
</info>
